Harry Ronchetti • Senior Product Engineer

+44 7546 258395 | harryronchetti@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/harry-ronchetti | github.com/hronchetti | harryronchetti.com

Summary

A determined and enthusiastic software engineer specialising in React-based technologies, data visualisation, and developer experience. Has managed engineering on several projects across different industries. Passionate about design and user experience. Strong interpersonal skills and history of consistently improving KPIs.

Experience

Head of Product & Technology • PolyBox

Dec 2024 - Present

Tech: Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, eCharts, Cube.js, Fivetran, Supabase, BigQuery

- Led engineering for a bespoke embedded analytics project that saved \$1800/mo in third-party services
- Modelled data for analytics from 8 different marketing platform APIs
- Built a forecasting feature for marketing ad spend trend identification and predictions

Founder (Passion Project) • WilderTrips

May 2022 - Present

Tech: Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Mapbox GL, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase

- Independently designed and built a road trip planning product that scaled to over 8500 free users and 750 paying customers
- Selected from over 400 applicants to receive £10k grant funding
- Achieved an average rating of 4.9/5 on Google from 49 reviews

Founding Engineer • Vizzly (Acquired)

Jun 2024 - Nov 2024 • 6 months

Tech: React.js, TypeScript, Emotion.js, Visx, D3.js, Cypress, Chromatic, Jest

- Built over 15 features and enhancements for exporting data, trend forecasting, conditional formatting, aggregating data, and interactive chart-building
- Managed QA and developer relations during a period of exponential growth
- Optimised chart build and render performance by 40% through memoisation
- Conducted 10 NPM package releases across 3 repos
- Created 2 new chart types for improved data visualisation

Freelance Product Designer & Software Engineer • Harry Ronchetti

Jun 2020 - Jun 2024 • 4 years

Tech: Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Mapbox GL, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase

- Led engineering and managed subcontractors for 8 projects
- Designed and built a renewable energy product that facilitated investment for 158 construction projects, totalling \$7.16bn in combined valuation

- Redesigned and built an independent local business marketplace that increased MRR by 72.6% within 6 months
- Redesigned and built a boiler installation product that led to 156% revenue growth within 6 months
- Reduced automation costs by 94% for a student tenancy lead generation product
- Improved onboarding completion by 68% for an OKR management product
- Designed and built an online healthcare training platform that generated £1.69m in sales over 18 months

Head of UX • NE6

Jun 2019 - Jun 2020 • 1 year

Tech: React.js, Gatsby.js, SCSS, Netlify, React PDF, React Table, React Beautiful DnD

- Led design and engineering for 7 software projects across 6 different industries, including insurance, recruitment, energy, and healthcare
- Directed solution architecture and project scoping for over 15 software projects
- Facilitated the company's transition from WordPress websites to software projects

Product Designer & Software Engineer • hedgehog lab

Feb 2018 - Jun 2019 • 1 year, 4 months

Tech: React.js, SCSS, GitLab, Netlify, React Calendar

- Designed a cosmetic surgery management product that modernised consultations through digital avatar drawing, resulting in 50% shorter appointments
- Led design on the agency's largest project to date, with a total contract value of £1m
- Supported UI development for 6 months to speed up project delivery

Software Designer • IBM

Jul 2016 - Jul 2017 • 1 year

• Designed an internal CMS for ibm.com that saved IBM £2m per year

Education

Web Design & Development (BSc) • Northumbria University

Sep 2014 - May 2018

- Grade: 1st (82%)
- Received the Employability Skills Award for Placement Students

Skills

React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Tailwind CSS, Emotion.js, Mapbox GL, Visx, eCharts, D3.js, SQL, Cube.js, Algolia, Airbyte, Fivetran, Cypress, Jest, Chromatic, SDKs, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase, Supabase, BigQuery, Agile, Scrum, Usability Testing, Design Workshops, Design Prototyping, Product Design, and Quality Assurance.

Interests

Product management, usability, public speaking, mentoring, and volunteering.